在本节中，我想谈谈对机器人的恐惧。作为我们可能拥有的机器人专家
In this section, I would like to talk about fear of Robots. As roboticists we might have
对一般人群的机器人的不同看法或观点。我们相信机器人
a different perception or view of robots to the general population. We believe that robots
在未来很有趣和酷，但也许不是每个人都有这种观点。我特别
are fun and cool in the future but perhaps not everybody shares that view. I particularly
喜欢这个广告，是为了道奇充电器，它出现在2013年。我无法告诉你
like this advertisement, was for Dodge Charger and it came out in 2013. I can’t show you
这里所有的视频，但广告正在利用人口普遍的不安
all of the video here but the advertisement is exploiting a general unease in the population
关于机器人的未来，并暗示我们不想要一辆自动驾驶汽车
about the future of robots and suggesting that we wouldn't want a self-driving car that
对人类来说，结局将非常非常糟糕。
is going to end very, very badly for human kind.
但是，有舞蹈机器人，所有人似乎喜欢在这里跳舞人形机器人
But then, there are dancing robots and everybody seems to love dancing humanoid robots so here
我们看到三个简单的人形机器人正在做一些精心设计的舞蹈。所以这是一种
we see three simple humanoid robots doing some choreographed dancing. So this is a kind
机器人通常不会引起普通人群的恐惧和厌恶。
of robot that generally doesn't invoke fear and loathing in the general population.
然后有机器人电影角色，如Wall-e和Eve，它们都没有威胁，
And then there are robotic movie characters such as Wall-e and Eve, which are quite non-threatening,
事实上，非常可爱。
and in fact, quite endearing.
与终结者特许经营这样的机器人相比，实际上相当
In contrast with robots like this from the Terminator franchise which are actually quite
可怕而且令人生畏。在这里，我们有一个拥有大量机器人的场景;这些机器人
scary and intimidating. Here we have a scene with a large number of robots; these robots
在这里，每个人看起来都很温和，他们看起来很人性化，他们很好
here individually look quite benign, they look quite human like, they have got nice
温柔的面部表情，但个人而言，我发现这个场景相当令人不安，我
gentle facial expressions but personally, I find this scene rather unsettling and I
我认为事实上它不仅仅是一个机器人，而是存在排的事实
think it is the fact that it is not just one robot but it is the fact that there is row
一排排机器人，我觉得不安。或许，也因为所有这些
upon row upon row of robots, which I find unsettling. Perhaps, also because all these
机器人看起来完全一样。
robots look exactly the same.
这是一位非常着名的机器人研究员和他的机器人克隆人。有些人可能会
Here is a very famous robotics researcher with his robotic clone. Some people may have
像这样的图像绝对没有问题，但其他人可能会发现这样的场景相当令人不安。
absolutely no problem with an image like this but other people might find such a scene rather unsettling.
这导致我们发现一种被称为UncannyValley的现象。UncannyValley是
That leads us to a phenomena which is called the Uncanny Valley. The Uncanny Valley is
这里的图表和水平访问表示我们有一个指示
represented by this graph here and on the horizontal access we have an indication of
机器人是如何生命的。
how life-like the robot is.
我们可以从完全没有生命的生活变成完全的生活
We can go from being not life-like at all to completely life-like
在垂直轴上，我们发现机器人很有吸引力
and in the vertical axis we have upwards that we find the robot attractive
向下我们发现机器人是令人厌恶的。
and downwards we find the robots to be repulsive.
现在，森林教授和我首先假设了神秘山谷的概念
Now, the notion of the Uncanny Valley was first hypothesized by Professor Mori and I
在2013年的IROS会议上有机会与他见面。
had the delightful opportunity to meet him at IROS conference in 2013.
因此，如果我们考虑UncannyValley假设，我们看到的是与人类的相似性
So if we consider the Uncanny Valley hypothesis, what we see is that as the likeness to a human
随着增加，我们发现机器人越来越有吸引力。但在某一点上，
being increases, we find the robot to be more and more attractive. But at a certain point,
然后我们发现它变得更像生活，我们发现它变得不那么有吸引力了
we then find that as it becomes more life-like we find it to become less attractive, perhaps
甚至变得令人厌恶。现在，它变得更像生活，它再次对我们有吸引力。
even to become repulsive. Now as it becomes more life-like still, it becomes, again, attractive to us.
如果机器人在移动，这种效果会被夸大。这是一个非常简单的人形机器人
And this effect is exaggerated if the robot is moving. Here is a very simplistic humanoid
机器人。它看起来不像人类。它有某种面孔，就是这样
robot. It doesn’t look much like a human at all. It’s got some sort of face, it’s
看起来像眼睛和嘴巴，大多数人对这样的机器人没有任何问题。
got what look like eyes and a mouth and most people have no problem with a robot like this.
它有点可爱;它有点复古。
It is kind of cute; it is a little bit retro.
如果我们有一个看起来像这样的机器人，看起来非常非常逼真，我们大多数人都会发现
If we had a robot that looks like this, looks very, very life-like, most of us would find
这也很有吸引力。但是，如果我们有一个看起来不太正确的机器人，那就是
that quite attractive as well. But if we have a robot that looks not quite right, something
有点偏，也许是眼睛里的东西不对，面部表情
a little bit off, maybe it is something in the eyes are not right, the facial expression
是不是很正确，我们发现像这样的机器人实际上是非常令人厌恶的。这是
is not quite right, we find a robot like this to be actually quite repellent. This is the
有趣的影响被称为UncannyValley。
interesting affect which is called the Uncanny Valley.
所以我现在要做的是推测一下这种对机器人的恐惧
So what I would like to do now, is to speculate a little bit about where this fear of robots
可能来自，特别是对人类机器人的恐惧。我相信很多
might come from, particularly the fear of robots in human form. I believe a lot of it
归咎于文化包袱，尤其是西方犹太教基督教文化;那里
is down to cultural baggage and particularly in the western Judeo Christian culture; there
可能是古代犹太传说中的傀儡的回声。傀儡是一个像人一样的人
are probably echoes of the ancient Jewish legend of the Golem. The Golem was a human-like
由圣人用粘土塑造的生物。Golem将为其创作者服务并保护
creature fashioned from clay by a Holy man. The Golem would serve its creators and protect
但偶尔他们会肆无忌惮地造成巨大的破坏和破坏。所以傀儡
them but occasionally they would run amok and cause great havoc and damage. So the Golem
是一个喜忧参半的祝福，它可以做得很好，但也可能做得很糟糕。
was a mixed blessing, it could do good but it could also do bad.
我相信，最近西方文化的影响来自弗兰肯斯坦的故事，
A more recent influence in western culture, I believe, comes from the story of Frankenstein,
玛丽雪莉1818年的小说，其中的生物打开了它的创造者弗兰肯斯坦博士和
Mary Shelly’s 1818 novel, in which the creature turns on its creator Dr. Frankenstein and
这个关于创造者的创造的故事是许多人的基础
this story of the creation turning on the creator is the foundation for many, many of
我们今天在科幻小说和科幻电影中读到的机器人故事。
the robot stories that we read today in science fiction books and in science fiction movies.
与日本的朋友和同事交谈，我感觉他们不那么害怕，
Talking to friends and colleagues in Japan, I get a sense that they are less fearful,
不那么以人类形式建造的机器吓倒了。我在这里走了一段路，
less intimidated by machines built in human form. I am going out on a bit of a limb here,
但我认为区别在于文化包袱;他们还没有成长起来的文化
but I think the difference is in the cultural baggage; they haven't grown up with the cultural
Golem的传统或Frankenstein故事的文化传统。我想，在他们的
tradition of the Golem or the cultural tradition of the Frankenstein story. I think, in their
宗教信仰他们可以在各种物体中看到生命力，无论它们是有生命的还是无生命的。
religious beliefs they can see a life force in all sorts of objects whether they are animate or inanimate.
所以这完全是我的猜测，但我认为这是文化的差异
So this is entirely speculation on my part, but I think it is the difference in the cultural
西方和东方的遗产也许让日本人更加宽容
heritage of the West and the East that perhaps makes people from Japan more accommodating
类人机器人形式的机器人，当然是技术推动创造人形机器人的地方
of robots in humanoid form and at certainly where the technological push to create humanoid
机器人最初来自。在人形机器人方面，西方确实在追赶。
robots first came from. The West has really been playing catch up when it comes to humanoid robots.